在上一集里
Previously on Transformers Prime:
预言中提到的星球串联现象
The planetary alignment
近在眼前
is nearly upon us.
我见过这座喷火的高山！
The flaming mountain in my visions...
从这个地方
A place from whence
我可以尽情地收集黑暗能量！
I am to harvest Dark Energon!
把他推过来 快！
I need him over here, now!
威震天 今天你必须服法 向塞博特恩和人类低头认罪
Megatron, today you answer for your crimes against Cybertron and humanity.
脉搏稳定下来了
Pulse rate is stabilizing.
看来我苦苦寻找的宇宙大帝之血
It seems the blood of Unicron I've been seeking
不是在星云之间 而是就在…我的脚下！
is not out there, but rather, right here!
为什么宇宙大帝之血 会从地底喷发出来？
Why is the blood of Unicron erupting from beneath the Earth?
这个问题嘛 擎天柱
A question, Optimus
你到坟墓里去思考吧！
that you shall take to your grave.
快！必须把他带回去
Quickly! We must pull him trough.
小隔 快 快 快走！！
Bulk, now, now, now!
好戏才刚刚开始！
This is merely the beginning!
现在我拥有的黑暗能量 足以唤醒宇宙大帝！
I now possess enough Dark Energon to reanimate Unicron himself!
哈哈哈…是的！哈哈哈…
Hahaha... yes! Hahaha...
放松 擎天柱
Easy, Optimus.
从症状看来 你感染了相当多的黑暗能量
From the looks of things, you've been exposed to a mass of amount of Dark Energon.
有人跟我同病相怜
I am not the only one.
嘿
Hey.
能活下来 是他命大
He's lucky to be alive.
威震天又找到黑煤球了？
Megatron found more of the dark stuff?
整整一火山的
A Volcano full.
问题是 他怎么找的？
The question is, how?
不 问题是 他想干嘛
No, the question is, what
传说中的宇宙大帝之血 为什么会出现在地球上
as in what in the world is the blood of Unicron doing here on Earth.
虎子们杀了只独角兽？
The 'Cons killed a Unicorn?
和白马一样 不过头上长角…
White horse with a horn on its head...
活蹦乱跳撒欢儿那种？
prances around all sparkly?
是“宇宙大帝” 远古的恶魔
Unicron, an ancient evil
他的血液在石化之后 形成了我们所说的那种黑暗能量…
whose fossilized blood comprises the matter which we call Dark Energon...
反正…传说里是这么讲的
... as legend would have it.
你是说 这个宇宙大帝是某种妖怪？
So you're saying, this Unicron is some kind of bogeyman?
妖怪？
Bogeyman?
大人捏造的 藏在衣柜里的怪物
Make believe creepy guy who hides in your closet.
不 达比护士
No, Nurse Darby.
宇宙大帝确实存在…过…
Unicron is very real... was.
就是说 虽然我相信他曾经存在
That is, while I do believe he once exited
可我不认同那种说法 据说…
I just don't subscribe to the theory that his...
构成他原始生命力的物质就是…拉夫感染的东西
primordial life force is the substance which... harmed Raf.
我听够了
I've heard it enough
杰克 过来 帮我把拉夫抱上车
Jack, please, help me get Raf into the car.
妈妈 他不是好多了吗
Mom, I thought he was doing better.
拉夫需要接受真人医生的检查
Raf needs to be examined by really doctors
拉夫的家人也要了解情况
and Raf's family needs to know what's happened.
他真正的家人
His real family.
妈妈 拉夫的家人没法保护他
Mom, Raf's family can't protect him.
不会像他们这样
Not like they can.
琼 我为自己的失败感到十分懊悔
June, it deeply grieves me that I have failed.
但我会尽我的一切所能来确保…
But I will do everything in my power to ensure
再也不会有人伤及我们的人类朋友 以及其他任何人类
that no harm comes to our human friends or any human ever again.
擎天柱 他们还是孩子
Optimus, they are children.
他们不属于你那个世界
They do not belong in your world.
他们应该关心自己的成绩 舞伴 青春痘…
They should be worrying about grades, prom dates, pimples...
不用担心生命危险！
not their own survival!
妈妈 黑暗能量正从地下向外井喷
Mom, Dark Energon is pouring out of the Earth.
这不正常
It doesn't do that.
可能关系到所有人的性命
This could be about everyone's survival
不光是我们的
not just ours.
你们必须跟我走
You're coming with me
三个人都走
all three of you.
他们不会再回来了
And they will not be coming back.
我理解
I understand.
这就完了？
That's it?
同甘共苦这么久 一句“再见”就打发了？
After all we've been through together, "see ya"?
我们不是可以自由选择吗？
What about our freedom to choose?
那是他们星球的东西
That may fly on their planet
在地球上行不通
but not here on Earth.
上车
Get in.
你以为我会坐一辆不会变形的汽车吗？
Do you really expect me to ride in a non-transforming vehicle?
神子 我是认真的
Miko, I'm serious.
你又不是我妈
You're not my mother.
神子…
Miko...
你也不是！
Neither are you!
好吧 我是你妈对吧
Well, I am yours.
我们走 杰克
Let's go, Jack.
她毕竟是你妈妈
She is your mom.
我要留下
I'm staying.
对不起
I'm sorry.
救护车 启动环陆桥
Ratchet, activate the GroundBridge.
谢了 不必
No, thank you.
擎天柱 能收到吗？
Prime, do you copy?
听到了 福勒探员
I hear you, Agent Fowler.
看新闻了吗？
Been watching the news?
大自然母亲的鼻孔发痒了
Mother nature's got a twitch in her breaches.
我们知道火山喷发的事
We know about the volcano.
那地震呢？
And the quakes?
七次大地震的震级分毫不差 而且跟火山喷发的时间完全吻合
Seven major temblors of the exact the same magnitude at the exact same time as the volcanic eruption.
地震分布在全球各个火山岩板块 按理说毫不相干 可它们却在…
All over the globe on different plutonic plates, in theory unrelated, if they hadn't happened...
同一时刻爆发
At the exact same time.
来看看 还有好消息
Check it out, more good news.
可怕的风暴让当地人目瞪口呆
Freak storms unlike any the region has seen
海啸使加拿大沿岸岌岌可危
tsunamis threaten the Canadian coast
雷暴也在戈壁滩上肆虐横行
while lightning storms pummel the Gobi Desert.
与此同时 电磁异常现象在城市电网中蔓延
Meanwhile, electro-magnetic anomalies plague urban power grids.
这些全球性的反常现象引发众人追问：\N怎么会这样 还能怎么样？
These abnormal global phenomena are leaving most to wonder: why now, and what next?
别告诉我 虎子们造了个天气控制仪
Don't tell me your 'Cons've built a weather machine.
能操纵天气？
One that powerful?
基本不可能
Highly unlikely.
我认为 黑暗能量在这个节骨眼上出现 决不是巧合
I do not believe the appearance of Dark Energon at this point in time to be coincidental.
一秒钟 两秒钟…
One 100, two 100...
你还好吧 拉夫？
You OK back there, Raf?
我看见闪电了
I saw lightning.
所以在数秒 等雷声…
I'm counting until the thunder...
嗯哼 看来要起风暴了
Huh, looks like a storm.
我的花园可遭殃了
My garden will love it.
拉夫 你没事吧？
Raf, are you ok?
嗯
Hmm.
那是什么？
What's that?
不…
No.
快点 快点 快点！
Come on, come on, come on!
小蜂让咱们爬到他手上！
Bee wants us to climb into his hand.
谢谢
Thank you.
他说“不客气”
He says "You are welcome."
喷涌你的生命之血 从深渊中崛起 和我融为一体！
Reverse of your very life blood rising from the depth to become one with me.
我们回来了
We are back.
我们也放心了
And we are glad.
你还好吗？
Are you alright?
我会好起来的 杰克…
I will be. Jack...
妈妈 我…
Mom, I...
我知道 我也是
I know, me too.
但你得禁足到30岁…25岁吧
But you're grounded till you're 30... 25.
各国领导人将这次奇异的天气状况 定性为全球性紧急事件
World leaders are classifying these bizarre weather patterns as a global emergency.
全球性的？
Global?
科学家们认为 该现象或多或少
And scientists believe the phenomena to be somehow
和近期的星球串联有关
related to the current planetary alignment.
有什么发现 擎天柱？
What have you learned, Prime?
你最好别跟我扯淡…
And you'd better not blow smoke up my ass...
达比小姐 真是个美丽的邂逅
Miss Darby, What a nice surprise.
福勒探员
Special Agent Fowler.
这就是我们的发现：跟火山中所谓的岩浆一样
We have learned this: as with the so called magma from the volcano
这些地震源自地壳以下极深的位置
these earthquakes originated far below the Earth's crust...
实际上 震源就在地核的正中央
from the very center of the Earth's core in fact.
一般的地震不是这样 对吧？
Quakes don't start there, do they?
细微的震颤呈固定的节奏起伏 就像是…
Tiny tremors rising and falling in a consistent pattern, almost like...
看在火种源的份上…
by the All Spark...
如果把这些数据点 转换成声音文件的话…
If I convert these data points to audio files...
怎么 什么东西？
What, what is it?
听
Listen.
停 声波 关掉它！
Stop, Soundwave. Turn it off.
我的脑袋要被它震裂了！
I can still hear it pounding in my brain!
塞博特恩人的心跳？
Cybertronian heartbeat?
这怎么可能？
How was that possible?
心脏泵的是血
A heart pumps blood.
地球内部没有能流通的东西 除了…
There is nothing inside the Earth to pump except...
宇宙大帝之血
Blood of Unicron.
我苏醒了！
I awakened.
好吧 先打住
Ok, hold on.
你的意思是 地底下有个活物
You mean something's living down there
就在地球里边？
inside our planet?
恐怕 地核并不是由岩浆组成的
I fear that the Earth's very core is not comprised of magma
这和人类科学有出入 但应该是黑暗能量
as your science has suggested, but of Dark Energon.
如果我们听到的是火种
And if we're hearing a spark
那么宇宙大帝就是崛起的黑暗势力 如预言所说
then Unicron is the rising darkness that the prophecy foretold.
好吧 怎么才能让这东西趴着不动呢？
So how do we stop this thing from rising?
恐怕预言对此并没有提及
That I'm afraid was not foretold.
地核里面怎么会有别的东西呢 而且还是活的？
How can something be in our Earth core and be alive?
这种情况不是没有先例
Such a thing is not unprecedented.
在创世之初
Before the beginning
世间只有原始天尊 以及宇宙大帝
there was Primus. And there was Unicron.
一方是造物主的化身
One, the incarnation of creation
而另一方 是毁灭的代言人
the other... of destruction.
亘古以来 原始天尊和宇宙大帝频繁交战
For eons, Primus and Unicron battled
二者实力不相上下 无数个回合难分胜负
the balance of power shifting between them more times than could be counted.
后来 原始天尊创造出十三位领袖――
Only by creating the Thirteen--
也就是我的几位前任领袖――
the original Primes preceded me--
才使自己最终战胜了宇宙大帝 并将他流放
was Primus finally able to defeat Unicron and cast him out.
原始天尊融入我们星球的核心
Primus became one with the very core of our planet
通过火种源之井创造生命
creating life through the Well of All Sparks
而宇宙大帝从此销声匿迹 如今却重返江湖
while Unicron was never to be heard from again... until now.
也许我们能找到这个钻地虎当年进入地心时 挖出的洞口
Maybe we can find the hole this kuggo Con left when he dug himself all the way down there
在里面填满炸药
and fill it full of explosives.
福勒探员
Agent Fowler
我认为 并非是宇宙大帝想在地球安家
I do not believe that Earth became Unicron's home
而是随着时间推移和重力作用
but rather that with time and gravitational force
星体碎屑聚拢在这个沉睡的巨人周围
debris collected around this slumbering titan.
这才造就了你们的地球
Forming your Earth itself.
他现在才睡醒 是因为星球串联形成了强大的磁吸力吗？
And he's only awakening now, due to the magnetic pull created by the planetary alignment?
好吧 宇宙大帝用几十亿年打了个盹儿 现在要干嘛？
Ok, what happens now when Unicron wakes up from his billion-year nap?
是啊 难道他伸个懒腰就“砰”的一声 地球灰飞烟灭了？
Yeah, does he stretch and ka-pow... Earth pup to dust?
你也不知道 对吧？
You don't know, do you?
我猜想 宇宙大帝的身躯应该和传说中一样 硕大无比
My guess is that Unicron has transcended physical form as we know it.
尽管如此 我们必须想办法确保这个“不可抗力”…
Nonetheless, we must find a way to ensure that this "force of nature" never fully awakens.
你们星球的命运在此一举
The fate of your planet depends upon it.
威震天陛下 货舱差不多被黑暗物质堆满了
Lord Megatron, our cargo hold is nearly filled with the dark substance.
我建议收兵
I recommend a retreat
战士们受黑暗能量的影响 越来越虚弱
the troops are growing weak from its effects.
但我却感到空前强大
And yet I grow stronger.
毒蜘蛛 你负责指挥 等我回来
Airachnid, you're in command until my return.
您这是要去哪儿 主人？
Your return from where, Master?
去会会宇宙大帝
From my audience with Unicron.
我感受到您的存在
I feel your presents
分享您尊贵的火种！
share your very spark.
我专程来拜访您 我的阁下和主人 全能的宇宙大帝！
I call on you as my Lord and Master, almighty Unicron.
谁在和我说话？
Who would speak to me?
您最谦卑的仆人
Your servant most humble
威震天 霸天虎的统帅
Megatron, leader of the Decepticons
您忠诚的使者
and your very Herald
是我运用黑暗能量 将你我联系在一起
the one who wielded the Dark Energon which binds us
使您再次苏醒 最终验证了预言！
to awaken you once again. The prophecy has been fulfilled.
我们即将共创一番大业 强强联手！
It is only the beginning of what we shall accomplish, together!
为您统治这颗星球 连同所有的生命 我将义不容辞！
For you shall rule this planet and those who walk upon it through me.
痴人说梦！
Pride for fool.
你竟然以为 自己有资格召唤我的生命力？
How dare you think yourself capable of summoning my life force?
我苏醒 是因为我感觉时机已到！
I rise because I have deemed my time.
主人 我无意以下犯上
Master, I did not mean to overstep.
闭嘴 蠕虫！
Silence, worm!
我无需一个下人插手此事
I have no need of your lowly assistance.
求您了 我的陛下
Please, my Lord.
我此生只为您效忠！
I exist only to serve you.
这是什么味道？
What is this I sense?
原始天尊的遗骨吗？这里也有？！
The taint of Primus? Here?!
那是擎天柱
That is Optimus
最后一个领袖 我们的死敌
the last of the Primes, our sworn enemy.
你口口声声说对我尽忠
You profess loyalty to me
却放任原始天尊的门徒活到今天？！
yet allow a disciple of Primus to live?!
我会为您消灭他！
I will destroy him for you!
他的惨叫会响彻…
His screams will be heard...
你的花言巧语我听够了
I grow weary of your prattle.
显然 如果你有实力消灭这个领袖
Surely if you had the power to destroy this Prime
你早该做到了
you would have done so already.
我还是亲自处理他吧
I will deal with him myself.
救护车 这个震源的特征和其他几处基本一致
Ratchet, this epicenter is consistent with the findings of the others.
地下矿藏非常丰富
Its terrain is rich in ore.
那是什么意思？
So what does that tell us?
这表示 你们地球上的天然金属矿
It follows that the natural medals in your Earth
就是宇宙大帝的扩展部分 相当于他的四肢
would be extensions of Unicron-- his limbs if you will.
这么说 他的确伸了个懒腰
So, he did have his morning stretch
所以才引发了地震
which is why these quakes happened.
擎天柱 我发现宇宙大帝火种的活性急剧增强
Optimus, I'm detecting a swell of Unicron's spark activity.
放心吧 救护车
Rest assured, Ratchet
我会提高警惕的
I will proceed with vigilance.
你认识我吗 原始天尊的追随者？
Do you know me, follower of Primus?
宇宙大帝 混沌制造者
Unicron, the Chaos Bringer.
很好
Good.
现在 称我为宇宙大帝――你的毁灭者！
Now know me as Unicron, your destroyer!
我恳求您听我一言 尊敬的宇宙大帝
I humbly request your ear, Lord Unicron.
一个如此低三下四的领袖 到底要说什么？
And what would a Prime be so compelled to say to me?
我的请求不是为自己
I make this appeal not for myself
而是为这个由您构建的星球 以及栖居其上的生命体
but for this planet which you constitute, and the beings who inhabit it.
人类依赖于您 才能繁衍生息
Human kind relies upon you, for life, sustenance.
您的复活只会导致这个物种走向毁灭
Your resurrection will only result in the destruction of a spices
而它恰恰是由您的伟大子孙孕育而生的
which evolved from the seeds of your very greatness.
那么你所说的这种人类
So this humankind of whom you speak
它们也算是我的后裔吗？
you consider them my progeny?
没错
Indeed.
是寄生虫！它们也会领教到我的怒火
Parasites! They, too, shall know my wrathful hand
但我要先和你把账算清！
once I am finished with you.
多日不见 原始天尊的氏族竟如此衰败 今天你陨落无疑！
The line of Primus has grown weak in my absence, and thus you shall fall.
汽车人固有一死
That outcome is inevitable
但今天不是时候！
but not on this day.
是的 原始天尊的门徒 就在今天
Yes, disciple of Primes, on this very day.
宇宙大帝之名独一无二 但我们都是宇宙大帝！
For Unicron may be one, but we all are Unicron.